Sometimes the last person on earth you want to be with
is the one person you can't be without.
Pride & Prejudice is a drama, romance film directed by Joe Wright.
A story of love and life among the landed English
gentry during the Georgian era.
Bennet is a gentleman living in Hertfordshire with his overbearing wife and five daughters, but if he dies their house will be inherited by a distant
cousin whom they have never met, so the family's future happiness and security is dependent on the daughters making good marriages.
Elizabeth Bennet, played by Keira Knightley.
Mr. Darcy, played by Matthew Macfadyen.
Mrs. Bennet, played by Brenda Blethyn.
Jane Bennet, played by Rosamund Pike.
Kitty Bennet, played by Carey Mulligan.
Lydia Bennet, played by Jena Malone.
Pride & Prejudice is a 2005 period romance film directed by Joe Wright, in his feature
directorial debut, based on Jane Austen's 1813 novel of the same name.
The film features five sisters from an English family of landed gentry as they
deal with issues of marriage, morality, and misconceptions.
Keira Knightley stars as Elizabeth Bennet, while Matthew
Macfadyen plays Mr Darcy, who falls in love with her.
Screenwriter Deborah Moggach initially attempted to make her script as faithful to the novel as
possible, writing from Elizabeth's perspective while preserving much of the original dialogue.
Wright encouraged greater deviation from the text,
including changing the Bennet family dynamics.
Wright and Moggach set the film in an earlier period and avoided depicting a "perfectly
clean Regency world", presenting instead a "muddy hem version" of the time.
It was shot entirely on location in England on an 11-week schedule.
Wright found casting difficult due to past
performances of particular characters.
The filmmakers had to balance who they thought was best for
each role with the studio's desire for stars.
Knightley was well known in part from her role in the Pirates of the Caribbean
film series, while Macfadyen had no international name recognition.
Produced by Working Title Films in association with StudioCanal, Pride & Prejudice was released on
16 September 2005 in the United Kingdom and on 11 November in the United States.
The film's themes emphasise realism, romanticism and family.
It was marketed to a younger, mainstream audience; promotional items noted that it came from the producers of
2001's romantic comedy Bridget Jones's Diary before acknowledging its provenance as an Austen novel.
Austen scholars opined that Wright's work created a new hybrid genre by blending
traditional traits of the heritage film with "youth-oriented filmmaking techniques".
Pride & Prejudice was successful at the box office, grossing
$121.6 million worldwide on a $28 million budget.
It received positive reviews from critics, with
praise for Knightley's performance.
It received four nominations at the 78th Academy Awards, including Best Actress for the
20-year-old Knightley, making her the third-youngest Best Actress nominee at the time.
The film received other accolades, including the BAFTA Award for Outstanding
Debut by a British Writer, Director or Producer for Wright.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book,
england, bachelor, family relationships, suitor.
The tone is emotional.